<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  == Copyright (C) 2011 Google Inc.
  ==
  == Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  == you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  == You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ==
  == http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ==
  == Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  == distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  == WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  == See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  == limitations under the License.
  -->

<objects>

  <title>Caja host page API documentation</title>

  <doc><p>This is the main API for host pages to use Caja for
  embedding untrusted guest code. A host page includes the
  <code>caja.js</code> script, for example:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-html">
&lt;script src="http://caja.appspot.com/caja.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</pre>
  <p>This places a singleton object, <code>caja</code>, in the host
  page's global namespace. The API of the <code>caja</code> object and
  the objects reachable from it is described here.</p></doc>

  <!-- 
    ************************************************************
    ** caja
    ************************************************************
  -->

  <object>
    <name>caja</name>

    <doc><p>The entry point for access to the Caja host page
    API.</p></doc>

    <!-- policy -->

    <property>
      <name>policy</name>
      <doc><p>A pre-configured set of policies (see
      <code>policy</code>) for use by host code, as an alternative to
      constructing a <code>uriPolicy</code> from scratch.</p></doc>
    </property>

    <!-- initialize -->

    <method>
      <name>initialize</name>
      <doc><p>Sets the default parameters for Caja.</p><p>This method
      must be called before any calls to <code>whenReady</code> or
      <code>load</code>. If either of these is called first, a built-in
      set of parameters will be used and any subsequent calls to
      <code>initialize</code> will throw. The resulting exceptions leave
      Caja in a consistent state.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>params</name>
        <doc><p>a map of configuration parameters. These include:</p><ul>
          <li><code>server</code>: a string giving the URL of the Caja
          server. This must match the location from which the
          <code>caja.js</code> script was sourced. For example, if the script
          was from <code>http://caja.appspot.com/caja.js</code>, then
          <code>cajaServer</code> must, correspondingly, be
          <code>http://caja.appspot.com/</code>.</li>
          <li><code>resources</code>: a string giving the URL of the location
          at which the Caja JavaScript runtime resources are found. If unspecified,
          this location is deduced from the <code>server</code> parameter.</li>
          <li><code>debug</code>: a boolean indicating whether to configure Caja
          for debugging. At this time, debugging support means that the code
          loaded into the browser will be pretty-printed for readability, rather
          than minified for speed.</li>
          <li><code>console</code>: an object that the Caja runtime is to use in
          place of the native browser's <code>console</code> global object. If
          unspecified, Caja will fall back to the native <code>console</code>,
          and silently suppress console logging if that is unavailable.</li>
          <li><code>log</code>: a function that the Caja runtime is to use in
          place of the native browser's <code>console.log</code> function. If
          unspecified, Caja will fall back to the <code>log</code> function in
          the supplied <code>console</code> object (see above). If unspecified,
          Caja will fall back to the browser's native <code>console.log</code>
          function. If that is unavailable, Caja will silently suppress console
          logging.</li>
        </ul></doc>
      </arg>
    </method>

    <!-- whenReady -->

    <method>
      <name>whenReady</name>
      <doc><p>Registers a function to be called back when Caja is
      ready to provide services.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>callback</name>
        <doc><p>a callback function.</p></doc>
      </arg>
    </method>

    <!-- load -->

    <method>
      <name>load</name>
      <doc><p>Load a new virtual Caja frame in which to run guest
      code.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>div</name>
        <doc><p>an HTML <code>&lt;div&gt;</code> which will contain
        the guest code's virtual HTML <code>document</code></p> <p>The
        caller may pass <code>undefined</code>, which causes the guest
        code to run with no virtual document (e.g., for running plain
        JavaScript without a UI).</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>uriPolicy</name>
        <doc><p>a <code>uriPolicy</code> object that is called
        whenever guest code attempts to gain access to an external
        URI.</p> <p>The caller may pass <code>undefined</code>, which
        disables all guest code's access to URIs, including via HTML
        such as <code>&lt;img src="..."&gt;</code> markup.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>callback</name>
        <doc><p>a <code>function(frame)</code> which will be called back 
        with a <code>frame</code> object when ready.</p></doc>
      </arg>
    </method>

    <!-- tame -->

    <method>
      <name>tame</name>
      <doc>
        <p>Tames a graph of defensive objects rooted at the supplied
        object. The result of taming is provided to guest code via the
        <code>apis</code> method of the <code>frame</code> object.</p>
        <p>For the most part, Caja automatically tames objects in a
        safe manner respecting the most common API choices.</p>
        <p><strong>Records and arrays.</strong> Records and arrays are
        tamed as read-only objects. Therefore, if you tame the
        record:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
var f = {
  x: 3,
  y: 4
};

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({ tamedF: aFrameGroup.tame(f) })
</pre>
          <p>guest code using the tamed form <code>tamedF</code> will
          be able to read the values of <code>x</code> and
          <code>y</code>, but will not be able to modify them:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
print(tamedF.x);
print(tamedF.y);
tamedF.x = 42;   // Error
tamedF.foo = 19; // Error
</pre>
          <p><strong>Functions:</strong> Functions are tamed as pure
          functions that are not supplied with a <code>this</code>
          variable. This means that, if you tame the function:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function f(x) { alert(this); alert(x); }
var t = aFrameGroup.tame(f);
</pre>
          <p>guest code using the tamed form <code>t</code> will be
          able to call your function, pass it arguments, and receive
          its returned value. However, the <code>this</code> value
          seen by your code will be a useless, empty record provided
          by Caja. The reason is that a function which modifies its
          <code>this</code> could be used by malicious guest code as a
          tool to manipulate objects that the guest code would not
          otherwise have had the authority to manipulate, and it is
          not common for JavaScript functions to check the progeny of
          their <code>this</code> variable on each invocation.</p>
          <p><strong>Recursion:</strong> Caja recursively traverses
          records and arrays and tames the values found inside them.
          Arguments passed from guest code to host functions are
          un-tamed, then the return value of the host function is
          tamed.</p>
        </doc>
      <arg>
        <name>aDefensiveObject</name>
        <doc>
          <p>a defensive object to be tamed. This object may have
          taming annotations on some of its components.</p>
        </doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>a tamed object suitable for presenting to guest
      code, representing the supplied defensive
      object.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- untame -->

    <method>
      <name>untame</name>
      <doc><p>Obtain the original defensive object corresponding to a
      tamed object.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>aTamedObject</name>
        <doc><p>a tamed object obtained via calling <code>tame</code>.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the original defensive object underlying
      <code>aTamedObject</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- markReadOnlyRecord -->

    <method>
      <name>markReadOnlyRecord</name>
      <doc><p>Marks a record such that guest code cannot make 
      modifications to the properties of the tamed form
      of the record. Only the supplied record is affected -- not any other object
      that may be connected to it. For example, in the following:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
var rw = { x: 3 };
var ro = { x : 4 }
caja.markReadOnlyRecord(ro);
var rot = aFrameGroup.tame(ro);
var rwt = aFrameGroup.tame(rw);
</pre>
        <p>guest code using the tamed value <code>rwt</code> would be
        allowed to modify the value of <code>x</code> or delete the
        property, or add a new property <code>y</code>. However, guest
        code using the tamed value <code>rot</code> would encounter an
        exception.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>f</name>
        <doc><p>a record in the host page.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the supplied <code>f</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

   <!-- markFunction -->

    <method>
      <name>markFunction</name>
      <doc><p>Marks a host function to be made callable from guest code when
      tamed. For example, in the following:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function ping(x) { alert('pinged ' + x); }
caja.markFunction(ping);

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({ ping: caja.tame(ping) })
</pre>
      <p>guest code would be able to use the value <code>ping</code> as a
      function, for example:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
ping('hello world');
</pre>
      <p>By default, functions from the host page are tamed as inert
      objects that have no useful behavior. This is a safety feature,
      because functions in the host page generally represent authority to
      affect the world. By calling <code>markFunction</code>, a host page
      author affirms that they have audited the behavior of the target
      function and have determined (a) that the authority it has is indeed
      okay to provide to the guest code; and (b) that the invariants upon which
      the correctness of the function depends cannot be violated by passing
      the function corrupted arguments. That last point requires, for example,
      that numeric indices are checked for bounds, and that strings passed
      from guest code are not used in a manner that could grant access to internal
      data structures.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>f</name>
        <doc><p>a function in the host page.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the supplied <code>f</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- markXo4a -->

    <method>
      <name>markXo4a</name>
      <doc><p>Mark a host function as suitable for taming as an
      <a
      href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exophora">exophora</a>,
      meaning, a function that receives any <code>this</code> value it
      is called on. Use only with care.</p>
      <p>Consider the following host code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function f(x) { this.dangerous = x; }
aFrameGroup.markXo4a(f);

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({ tamedF: aFrameGroup.tame(f) })
</pre>
      <p>Guest code using the function <code>tamedF</code> would be able to
      set the property <code>dangerous</code> on <em>any</em> object of its
      choosing, regardless of any policies to the contrary. So, if <code>victim</code>
      were an object that relied on its <code>dangerous</code> property and did
      not make that available to external clients, the following guest code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
victim.method = tamedF;
victim.method(42);
</pre>
      <p>or even:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
tamedF.apply(victim, [42]);
</pre>
      <p>would set the <code>dangerous</code> property of <code>victim</code>
      to the value <code>42</code>, regardless of policies to the contrary.</p>
      <p>The rule for when an exophora is safe is that it
      <em>only</em> gets or sets whitelisted properties of the
      <code>this</code> value on which it is called, in other words,
      properties that do not interfere with any object's internals. It
      may do so because the property (such as <code>dangerous</code> above)
      is known to always be safe, or because the function itself (like
      <code>f</code> above) contains enough internal checks to make sure it
      never does the wrong thing.</p>
      <p>In general, true reasons for using exophora are rare. We
      advise the use of other, safer mechanisms, with exophora as a
      last resort.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>f</name>
        <doc><p>a function in the host page.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the supplied <code>f</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- markCtor -->

    <method>
      <name>markCtor</name>
      <doc><p>Marks a host function as a constructor that, when tamed,
      can be used by guest code using the <code>new</code> operator,
      with correct behavior of <code>instanceof</code>. Consider the
      following host code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function Ctor(x) { this.x = x; }
Ctor.prototype.getX = function() { return this.x; };
Ctor.prototype.setX = function(x) { this.x = x; };

function SubCtor(x, y) { Ctor.call(this, x); this.y = y; }
SubCtor.prototype = new Ctor(0);
SubCtor.prototype.getY = function() { return this.y; };
SubCtor.prototype.setY = function(y) { this.y = y; };
</pre>
      <p>In a case where <code>Ctor</code> and <code>SubCtor</code>
      are to be made available to guest code, it is necessary to
      annotate them so that Caja can tame them correctly. Each
      constructor must be marked with <code>markCtor</code> and, if a
      constructor has a superclass, that must be provided as the
      second argument to <code>markCtor</code>. For example:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
aFrameGroup.markCtor(Ctor);
aFrameGroup.markCtor(SubCtor, Ctor);

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({
  TamedCtor: tame(Ctor),
  TamedSubCtor: tame(SubCtor)
})
</pre>
      <p>When guest code creates instances of these constructors,
      e.g., by calling:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
var o = new TamedCtor(19);
</pre>
      <p>Caja will ensure that the instances, like <code>o</code> in
      the example, are tamed correctly.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>c</name>
        <doc><p>a constructor in the host page.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the supplied <code>c</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- grantMethod -->

    <method>
      <name>grantMethod</name>
      <doc><p>Marks a function property on an object and its prototype chain
      descendants such that tamed code can
      call it as a method on its parent object. A method (as opposed to a pure
      function) is called with a properly bound <code>this</code> value.</p>
      <p>By default, to prevent confusion and enhance defensibility, if guest
      code has access to a tamed object <code>o</code>, and there exists a property
      <code>p</code> on <code>o</code> such that the value of <code>o.p</code> is
      a function, then if guest code invokes the function by writing <code>o.p()</code>,
      the implementation of the function pointed to by <code>o.p</code> does <em>not</em>
      receive <code>o</code> as its value of <code>this</code> (it receives some useless
      value instead).</p>
      <p>Host code can use <code>grantMethod</code> to override this default. A common
      use case is when taming idiomatic JavaScript classes. Consider the host code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function Ctor(x) { this.x = x; }
Ctor.prototype.getX = function() { return this.x; };
Ctor.prototype.setX = function(x) { this.x = x; };
</pre>
      <p>Assume the host page wishes to allow guest code to call
      <code>getX</code> and <code>setX</code> on
      instances of <code>Ctor</code> and for <code>this</code> in these functions to
      be bound correctly. The host page should do:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.markCtor(Ctor);
caja.grantMethod(Ctor.prototype, "getX");
caja.grantMethod(Ctor.prototype, "setX");

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({
  TamedCtor: tame(Ctor),
})
</pre>
      <p>Guest code can then make the following calls to <code>getX</code> and
      <code>setX</code> and expect them to work:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
var o = new TamedCtor(19);
o.getX();
o.setX(22);
</pre>
      </doc>
      <arg>
        <name>o</name>
        <doc><p>an object (often but not always the prototype of a constructor).</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>name</name>
        <doc><p>the name of a property on object <code>o</code> (or anticipated objects
	having <code>o</code> as their prototype).</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the supplied <code>o</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- grantRead -->

    <method>
      <name>grantRead</name>
      <doc><p>Marks a property on an object and its prototype chain decendants such that
      tamed code can read the property on its parent object. A common
      use case is when taming idiomatic JavaScript classes. Consider the host code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function Ctor(x) { this.x = x; }
</pre>
      <p>Assume the host page wishes to allow guest code to read the <code>x</code>
      property on instances of <code>Ctor</code>. The host page should do:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.markCtor(Ctor);
caja.grantRead(Ctor.prototype, "x");

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({
  TamedCtor: tame(Ctor),
})
</pre>
      <p>Guest code can then read <code>x</code> as follows and expect the
      read operation to work:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
var o = new TamedCtor(19);
o.x;
</pre>
      </doc>
      <arg>
        <name>o</name>
        <doc><p>an object (often but not always the prototype of a constructor).</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>name</name>
        <doc><p>the name of a property on object <code>o</code> (or anticipated objects
	having <code>o</code> as their prototype).</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the supplied <code>o</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- grantReadWrite -->

    <method>
      <name>grantReadWrite</name>
      <doc><p>Marks a property on an object and its prototype chain decendants such that
      tamed code can read and write the property on its parent object. A common
      use case is when taming idiomatic JavaScript classes. Consider the host code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function Ctor(x) { this.x = x; }
</pre>
      <p>Assume the host page wishes to allow guest code to read and write the <code>x</code>
      property on instances of <code>Ctor</code>. The host page should do:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.markCtor(Ctor);
caja.grantReadWrite(Ctor.prototype, "x");

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({
  TamedCtor: tame(Ctor),
})
</pre>
      <p>Guest code can then read and write <code>x</code> as follows and expect the
      read and write operations to work:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>guest code</strong> */
var o = new TamedCtor(19);
o.x = 23;
o.x;
</pre>
      </doc>
      <arg>
        <name>o</name>
        <doc><p>an object (often but not always the prototype of a constructor).</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>name</name>
        <doc><p>the name of a property on object <code>o</code> (or anticipated objects
	having <code>o</code> as their prototype).</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the supplied <code>o</code>.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- unwrapDom -->

    <method>
      <name>unwrapDom</name>
      <doc><p>Unwrap the value a DOM node provided to host code from guest code.</p>
      <p>When guest code attempts to pass to host code a DOM node across the taming
      boundary, what is actually passed is a wrapper object holding the DOM node.
      This container object must be opened using <code>unwrapDom</code> to get at the
      underlying DOM node.</p>
      <p>Consider the host code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function operateOnNode(n) { }
caja.markFunction(operateOnNode);

/* then provide to guest code: */
aFrame.api({
  operateOnNode: tame(operateOnNode)
})
</pre>
      <p>Assume that guest code running within a Caja tamed HTML DOM hands a DOM
      node back to the host code using the <code>operateOnNode</code> function, as follows:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-html">
&lt;!-- <strong>guest markup</strong> --&gt;
&lt;div id="aNode"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
  operateOnNode(document.getElementById('aNode'));
&lt;/script&gt;
</pre>
        <p>To gain access to the actual underlying DOM node, the host function
	<code>operateOnNode</code> would need to be implemented as follows:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
function operateOnNode(n) {
  /* 'n' is an opaque wrapper object */
  var r = caja.unwrapDom(n);
  /* 'r' is now the actual underlying DOM node */
}
</pre>
      </doc>
      <arg>
        <name>n</name>
        <doc><p>an opaque wrapper for a DOM node, created by Caja when guest code
	passes a DOM node to host code.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>the actual underlying DOM node.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <!-- examples -->

    <example>
      <title>Setting defaults</title>
      <doc>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.initialize({
  cajaServer: 'http://caja.appspot.com/',
  debug: false
});
</pre>
        <p>Sets the defaults to point to <code>caja.appspot.com</code>
        without debug support.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

    <example>
      <title>Erroneous <code>initialize</code></title>
      <doc>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.whenReady(function() { /* ... */ });
caja.initialize({ /* ... */ });
</pre>
        <p>The call to <code>initialize</code> throws since
        <code>whenReady</code> has already been called.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

    <example>
      <title>Erroneous <code>initialize</code></title>
      <doc>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.load( /* ... */ );
caja.initialize({ /* ... */ });
</pre>
        <p>The call to <code>initialize</code> throws since
        <code>load</code> has already been called.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

    <example>
      <title>Incorrect taming</title>
      <doc>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
/* in a top-level script */
caja.markFunction( /* ... */ );
caja.tame( /* ... */ );
</pre>
        <p>Both calls to the <code>caja</code> object throw since,
        when the main scripts in the page are being evaluated, the
        <code>caja</code> object is not yet ready.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

    <example>
      <title>Successful taming</title>
      <doc>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
/* in a top-level script */
caja.whenReady(function() {
  caja.markFunction( /* ... */ );
  caja.tame( /* ... */ );
});
</pre>
        <p>The calls to <code>markFunction</code>
	and <code>tame</code> succeed.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

    <example>
      <title>Running guest HTML from a URL</title>
      <doc>
        <p>Assume the host page has some HTML like the following:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-html">
&lt;!-- <strong>host page markup</strong> --&gt;
&lt;div id="guestDiv"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</pre>
        <p>Then the following code in the page:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.initialize({ cajaServer: 'http://caja.appspot.com' });
caja.load(
    document.getElementById('guestDiv'),
    undefined,  // no network access
    function(frame) {
      frame.code('http://foo.com/guest.html')
           .run(function() {
             alert('Guest code is running!');
           });
    });
</pre>
<p>loads <code>http://foo.com/guest.html</code> as a guest page into
the pre-arranged <code>&lt;div&gt;</code> and <code>alert</code>s when
the guest page is loaded.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

    <example>
      <title>Running guest JavaScript from content</title>
      <doc>
        <p>The following code in a host page:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
caja.initialize({ cajaServer: 'http://caja.appspot.com' });
caja.load(
    undefined,  // no DOM access
    undefined,  // no network access
    function(frame) {
      frame.code(
               'http://example.com/default.js',  // dummy URL
               'application/javascript',
               '(x + y);')  // input source code
           .api({ x: 3, y: 4 })
           .run(function(result) {
             alert(result);
           });
    });
</pre>
        <p>will run the provided source, pass it the supplied values
        of <code>x</code> and <code>y</code>, and <code>alert</code>
        the result of the computation, which would be the number
        <code>7</code>.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

    <example>
      <title>Providing a restricted user alert function</title>
      <doc>
        <p>Imagine a host page wishes to give guest code the ability
        to call <code>alert</code>, but not to abuse it by calling it
        too many times. Assume the host page has HTML like the
        following:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-html">
&lt;!-- <strong>host page markup</strong> --&gt;
&lt;div id="guestDiv"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</pre>
        <p>Then the following code:</p>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
var alertCount = 0;
var restrictedAlert = function(s) {
  if (alertCount === 2) { return; }
  alertCount++;
  alert(String(s));
};

caja.initialize({ cajaServer: 'http://caja.appspot.com' });
caja.whenReady(function() {
  caja.markFunction(restrictedAlert);
});

caja.load(
    document.getElementById('guestDiv'),
    undefined,  // no network access
    function(frame) {
      frame.code('http://foo.com/guest.html')
           .api({ alert: caja.tame(restrictedAlert) })
           .run(function() {
             alert('Guest code is running!');
           });
    });
</pre>
        <p>will run the provided source, allowing it to call an
        <code>alert</code> function that will seem like the
        browser-provided version, but all but the first three attempts
        to call it will be silent no-ops.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>

  </object>

  <!-- 
    ************************************************************
    ** frame
    ************************************************************
  -->

  <object>
    <name>frame</name>

    <doc><p>Object representing a virtual frame in which Caja runs
    guest code. Contains a confined ECMAScript 5 JavaScript context,
    with an optional confined DOM <code>document</code>.</p></doc>

    <method>
      <name>cajoled</name>
      <doc><p>Specifies that this <code>frame</code> is to run code
      that has been pre-compiled ("cajoled") by the Caja
      compiler. This is used for cases where the host code is
      integrating tightly with Caja; has run the Java code directly
      (either via an API or by command line invocation) to compile the
      code; and wishes to inject it for use.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>uri</name>
        <doc><p>The base URI of the original code, to be used when
        virtualizing the DOM.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>js</name>
        <doc><p>The cajoled JavaScript output from the Caja
        compiler.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>html</name>
        <doc><p>The cajoled HTML output from the Caja
        compiler.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>this <code>frame</code> object.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <method>
      <name>code</name>
      <doc><p>Specifies that this <code>frame</code> is to run code
      supplied by the host. The Caja system in the page will use its
      connection to the server to compile ("cajole") the supplied
      code.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>uri</name>
        <doc><p>The URI of the original (un-cajoled) content.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>mimeType</name>
        <doc><p><strong>Optional.</strong> The MIME type of the
        original (un-cajoled) content. Accepted values are
        <code>text/html</code> and
        <code>application/javascript</code>.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <arg>
        <name>content</name>
        <doc><p><strong>Optional.</strong> The literal content to be
        run. If not supplied, Caja will retrieve the content using the
        <code>uri</code> parameter.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>this <code>frame</code> object.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <method>
      <name>api</name>
      <doc><p>Specifies the APIs that will be provided to the guest
      code.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>o</name>
        <doc><p>an object containing named fields, each of which
        becomes a top-level API that guest code can use. Each such
        object should be tamed using the <code>tame</code>
        method.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>this <code>frame</code> object.</p></returndoc>
    </method>
    
    <method>
      <name>run</name>
      <doc><p>Runs code in the frame according to the information
      provided by previous calls to some combination of
      <code>code</code>, <code>cajoled</code> and
      <code>api</code>.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>callback</name>
        <doc><p>a <code>function(result)</code> wich will be called
        back with the <em>completion value</em> of the code executed
        in this frame. HTML has no completion value, while the
        completion value of JavaScript is the same as the result of
        evaluating it using the standard <code>eval</code>
        operator.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>this <code>frame</code> object.</p></returndoc>
    </method>
    
  </object>

  <!-- 
    ************************************************************
    ** policy
    ************************************************************
  -->

  <object>
    <name>policy</name>

    <doc><p>A pre-configured set of policies for use by host
    code.</p></doc>

    <property>
      <name>net.NO_NETWORK</name>
      <doc><p>A <code>uriPolicy</code> that disallows all network access.</p></doc>
    </property>

    <property>
      <name>net.ALL</name>
      <doc><p>A <code>uriPolicy</code> that allows all network access.</p></doc>
    </property>

    <method>
      <name>net.only</name>
      <doc><p>Constructs a <code>uriPolicy</code> that allows only access to a
      specified URI.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>uri</name>
        <doc><p>the sole URI to be allowed.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>a <code>uriPolicy</code> allowing access only to the specified
      URI.</p></returndoc>
    </method>
    
  </object>

  <!-- 
    ************************************************************
    ** uriPolicy
    ************************************************************
  -->

  <object>
    <name>uriPolicy</name>

    <doc><p>An object that is called to determine whether, and how,
    guest code should be allowed to gain access to external
    URIs.</p></doc>

    <method>
      <name>rewrite</name>
      <doc><p>Determines whether the given URI should be
      permitted.</p></doc>
      <arg>
        <name>uri</name>
        <doc><p>a fully qualified candidate URI, represented as a
        <code>string</code>.</p></doc>
      </arg>
      <returndoc><p>a truthy value iff the candidate URI is one which
      should be accessible to the guest code.</p></returndoc>
    </method>

    <example>
      <title>Restricted domain</title>
        <doc>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
var aPolicy = {
  rewrite: function(uri) {
    return /http:\/\/example\.com/\.*/.test(uri);
  }
};
</pre>
        <p>Constructs a <code>uriPolicy</code> which only allows
        access to HTTP URL paths under the <code>example.com</code>
        domain.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>
    
    <example>
      <title>Unrestricted</title>
        <doc>
<pre class="prettyprint lang-javascript">
/* <strong>host page code</strong> */
var aPolicy = {
  rewrite: function(uri) { return true; }
};
</pre>
        <p>Constructs a <code>uriPolicy</code> which allows
        unrestricted access.</p>
      </doc>
    </example>
    
  </object>
      
</objects>
